Finding Aid for Albert C. Jacobs papers, 1909-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Albert C. Jacobs papers 1909-1970
Jacobs, Albert Charles, 1900-1976.
10 linear feet
851550 Aa 2
College administrator; correspondence, newspaper clippings, and printed materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Albert C. Jacobs (donor no. 5112 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Albert C. Jacobs was a professor of law at Columbia University. From 1947 to 1949, he served as provost of the university under president Dwight D. Eisenhower. From 1947 to 1953, he served as chancellor at the University of Denver. He then became president of Trinity College, Hartford, Connecticut, serving from1953 to 1968.
The Jacobs papers consist of correspondence, clippings, and speeches from his career as law professor and college administrator. Most of the papers are of a personal nature and provide little documentation of his activities at either Columbia, University of Denver, or Trinity College. The address series is valuable for its discussions of higher education from the 1940s to the 1960s.
Subjects:
Columbia University.; Education--United States.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Jacobs, Albert Charles, 1900-1976.; Trinity College (Hartford, Conn.); Universities and colleges--United States.; University of Denver.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Jacobs, Albert Charles, 1900-1976.; Jacobs family.; Romulo, Carlos P. (Carlos Peña), 1899-1985.; Trinity College (Hartford, Conn.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - General, undated and 1909-1966, 27 folders (Box 1)
  - General, 1967-1970, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Invitations of the University Club of New York City to meet Albert C. Jacobs, Chancellor-elect of the University of Denver (Box 2)
  - Columbia University correspondence, 1946-1949 (Box 2)
  - Letters re leaving Columbia University, 1949, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - University of Denver letters
    - 1949-1951, 7 folders (Box 2)
    - 1952-1953, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Trinity College letters, 1950-1954, 7 folders (Box 3)
- Newspaper clippings
  - Columbia University, 1946-1949 (Box 3)
  - 1953-1955, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - 1956-1968, 19 folders (Box 4)
  - 1946 (Assistant to the President of Columbia for Veterans Affairs) (Box 5)
  - 1946-1949 (Columbia University) (Box 5)
  - 1950-1953 (University of Denver), 5 folders (Box 5)
  - 1953 (Trinity College) (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 8 folders (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 15 folders (Box 6)
- Publications
  - Programs, pamphlets, and other printed material (Box 6)
  - Programs, pamphlets, and other printed material (Box 7)
- Addresses
  - 1949-1957, 19 folders (Box 8)
  - 1958-1965, 19 folders (Box 9)
  - 1966-1968, 5 folders (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, newspaper clippings, and printed material (Box 10)
  - Photographs (Box 10)
    (photograph of Jacobs and family with Dwight D. Eisenhower; also photograph of Jacobs with Carlos P. Romulo and others at Trinity College convocation.)